Guide to the Kathy Hopwood Papers, 1970-2015 and undated RL.11387
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Publications, 1972-2004 and undated
  - Applied Combat Martial Arts (ACMA) Instructor Certification Manual (Box 6)
  - Choices: A Sexual Assault Prevention Workbook for Persons Who Are Deaf And Hard of Hearing (Box 7)
  - Special Fight (Box 7)
  - Self Defense & Empowerment News, 1993-1996 (Box 7)
  - Model Mugging News, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Women's Self Defense Manual (Box 7)
  - Personal Safety Skills: Prevention, Confrontation, and Intervention (Box 7)
  - Women Against Rape Publications (Box 7)
  - Books on Women's Martial Arts (Box 1, Box 15, Box 17, Box 18, Box 20, Box 21)
  - Periodical Issues on Women's Self-Defense, 1979-1990s and undated (Box 19)
  - Karate Basics Manual (Box 23)
  - Martial Arts History Manual (Box 23)
  - Shorin-Ryu History and Evolution Manual (Box 23)
  - Weapons Manual (Box 23)
  - Legalities of Self-Defense (Box 24)
  - Mace and Chemical Sprays (Box 24)
  - Martial Arts Portraits (Box 27)
  - Workplace Violence Resources (Box 27)
  - Defuse Violence Workshops Materials (Box 27)
- Audio Visual Materials, 1973-2015
  Scope contents here.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to request the production of listening or viewing copies.
  - Photographs, 1973-2015
    - Early Training Years, 1973 (Box 25)
    - Day Before Black Belt Test, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test - Chapel Hill, NC, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Southern Women's Martial Arts Weekend with Marianna Kaufman - Chapel Hill, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Beth Seigler and Kathy Hopwood Martial Arts Working Out, 1983 (Box 25)
    - Public Demonstrations of Martial Arts/Self-Defense (Box 25)
    - TWKA First Renovations Prior to Opening First Dojo in Durham, 1983 (Box 25)
    - First Dojo - Mangum St., Durham (Box 25)
    - Rape Awareness March and Rally - Chapel Hill and Carrboro, NC, 1984 (Box 25)
    - Self Defense/Martial Arts Demonstrations - Durham YMCA, 1986 (Box 25)
    - TWKA/SafeSkills members at NWMAF Special Training Camps, 1980 (Box 25)
    - TWKA Guest Instructor, Jaye Spiro, 1985 (Box 25)
    - TWMA Guest Instructor, Bobbi Snyder, 1980s (Box 25)
    - YMCA Demo by TWMA Dojo, 1986 (Box 25)
    - TWMA Staff Photographer, Jamie Francis for Durham Morning Herald, 1986 (Box 25)
    - Options - TWMA Program for Duke Orientation, 1989 (Box 25)
    - Renovations for Opening of Second Dojo Location in Durham, 1992-2008 (Box 25)
    - SafeSkills Belt Test, 1992-2008 (Box 25)
    - Kate Watters - Board Breaking Class and Karate Stances at Shannon Plaza, 1993 (Box 25)
    - Girls' Karate Class and Summer Camps at Shannon Plaza, 1993-1994 (Box 25)
    - EmPOWERment Padded Mock Attacker Program, 1990 (Box 25)
    - Lisa Sedaris Promotional Portraits, 1992-1997 (Box 25)
    - Kathy Hopwood and Beth Seigler - Self-Defense Techniques (Box 25)
    - Beth Seigler and Kathy Hopwood Release Techniques, 1992 (Box 25)
    - Beth Seigler, 1992 (Box 25)
    - SafeSkills Dojo Events, 1992-2008 (Box 25)
    - SafeSkills Children's Karate Classes, 1992-2008 (Box 25)
    - SafeSkills Dojo Events, 2008-2015 (Box 25)
    - Beth Seigler and Kathy Hopwood Corporate/Professional Portraits (Box 25)
    - Beth Seigler and Kathy Hopwood Teaching Self-Defense (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp (Box 25)
    - Kathy Hopwood and Beth Seigler Arnis Demo and First NC Seminar with Prof. Remy Presas, 1989 (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test; Terry Graedon - SafeSkills, Shannon Plaza, 1997 (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test; Karen O'Neal - SafeSkills, Shannon Plaza (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test; Tweedy Tattersall - SafeSkills, Shannon Plaza (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test; Hannah Chapinl - SafeSkills, Shannon Plaza, 2000 (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test; Naomi Adlandl - SafeSkills, Shannon Plaza (Box 25)
    - Black Belt Test; Alexis Groner - SafeSkills, Shannon Plaza (Box 25)
    - NWMAF - Photos Used in First Brochure, 1976 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp at The Lawrenceville School - Lawrenceville, NJ, 1983 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp at Edinboro University - Edinboro, PA, 1984 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp at William Smith College - Geneva, NY, 1985 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp at Yale University - New Haven, CT, 1986 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp at Kent State - Kent, OH, 1987 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Teacher's Conference at Hobart and William Smith Colleges - Geneva, NY, 1988 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp - Geneva, NY, 1988 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Special Training Camp at Albertus Magnus College - New Haven, CT, 1990 (Box 25)
    - NWMAF Covers and Graphics (Box 25)
    - Belt Tests, 1990s (Box 30)
      3 CDs
    - First Annual Special Training Camp for Women Group Photo (Box 33)
    - Beth Seigler and Students, Mangum St. Dojo, 1980s (Box 33)
  - Audiocassettes and Videocassettes, 1980s-2015
    - Spectra Feminist Media Project Video - Letter Video Tape (Box 3)
    - TWKA Video Reel (Box 3)
    - 2 Self-Defense Video Tapes (Box 3)
    - Box of Tapes and Casettes (Box 8)
    - Videotapes of Demonstrations, Classes, and Summer Kid's Camps., 1984-1990s (Box 29)
    - emPOWERment Videos, 1992-1997 (Box 30)
    - Black Belt Tests, 1980s-2015 (Box 30)
    - National Women's Martial Arts Federation Videos (Box 31)
    - Mainstream Self-Defense Videos (Box 32)
    - Audiocassettes of Local Radio Shows, Including WUNC's The People's Pharmacy, Featuring Hopwood and Seigler, 1989-1994 (Box 33)
- Kathy Hopwood papers website